at the time of recording this video
dodge coin is worth 30
cents now hopefully by the time you
watch this video the bubble has already
popped
without too many people getting hurt now
i have mixed feelings about dodge coin
on one hand i think it's funny i think
what
elon musk is doing is hilarious and also
thanks to dodgecoin many people are
coming
into the crypto ecosystem and they are
talking about wallets and they are going
to look into other coins and it's good
for
adoption but on the other hand those
coins attracting the kind of people that
just want to gamble and those are the
people that are super
easily scammed also dodgecoin makes this
whole industry look like a joke it makes
it look like it's run by 14 year olds
with credit cards
now just to be clear dodgecoin is not a
scam
a scam usually means that people are
lying to you about the real value of
something
but in the case of dodgecoin the team of
developers and the community have
always been honest with us dot coin is a
joke coin it was made to be not take it
seriously it's all about
the memes now i'm not saying don't buy
dodge coin i'm saying do whatever you
want as long as you do your research and
as long as you are self-aware
for example i don't know if you knew
this but dodge coin is an infinite
currency there are 14 million dodge
coins being printed
every day that's crazy compared to for
example
bitcoin where in bitcoin there is a
maximum amount of bitcoins
forever of 21 million but we can't use
bitcoin
can we i mean it's really slow five
transactions maximum per second and also
is very
eco-unfriendly it wastes so much energy
like i told you on the previous video
so what's the alternative between a
cryptocurrency like dodge coin which is
a joke and something so slow and so econ
friendly like bitcoin anonymous
nicolas and welcome to the video number
eight
wow it's been two months that's insane
of this series where i'm talking about
crypto bitcoin blockchain in all this
industry for developers and
beginners thank you so much for being
here if you're enjoying this series so
far consider leaving a like
and subscribing it really helps support
the channel on the last video we talked
about the problems of the crypto
industry from the government regulation
point of view and from the scamming and
cheating point of view
on this video we're going to talk about
the technical problems what developers
care about speed scalability programming
languages
all that and also we have an
announcement at the end of the video so
make sure you stick around to know
now bitcoin is a first generation
blockchain a first generation blockchain
is a blockchain that uses proof of work
to secure itself the goal of bitcoin was
to be internet money
that nobody could hack now did they
succeed yes
they did but bitcoin uses proof of work
to secure
the network as we saw on previous videos
now proof of
work requires your computer to work in
order to secure the network
and to get rewards from the network but
this work usually comes in the form of
electricity from your computer and the
more the network grows
the more energy it needs and the more it
damages the environment now you could
make the point that bitcoin is
eco-friendly or will be eco-friendly
once everything is running on
solar energy and that might be true but
that's not the case right now like for
example china
last week had a blackout on one of the
coal mines they had a mine
that mine got shot down and with that
shutdown of that mine
bitcoin lost 30 of its hash rate
china is responsible for 50
of the hash rate of bitcoin network so
for bitcoin to be really eco-friendly
you will have to take for example these
coal mines in china and replace them
with solar energy
also maybe proof of work is not that
decentralized and that
safe if most of the hash rate more than
of that would be located only in one
country that has
cheap electricity and cheap electronics
so to conclude
bitcoin is the most successful and
secure
cryptocurrency out there is the most
valuable as well
but this comes at the cost of being slow
and
energy inefficient it's also not
programmable we cannot do anything with
it the only thing we can do is send it
between each other it's
boring sort of like gold we can't have
defy
or any of these on bitcoin it's just not
possible now second generation
cryptocurrencies are the ones that
introduce the concept of
smart contracts we talked about smart
contracts before and as we know there
isn't only one cryptocurrency with smart
contracts there are actually
many of them very different but the one
that is the most famous one
is a theory ethereum was started by
people that wanted to do
more with bitcoin but couldn't the
reason why they couldn't is because
bitcoin
is not designed to be updated and also
the developers of bitcoin don't want to
update the way the network works
bitcoin is designed to run as is running
right now forever
is sort of like gold really but now
ethereum has one more goal on top of
bitcoin's goal
ethereum wants to be a world shared
computer
a programmable unhackable shared backend
where humans encode can interact create
lock do whatever they want with coins
now this creates other problems and that
is that
if we can build things on top of
ethereum for example
that means that the network is going to
be very very busy because we don't only
send and receive money like on bitcoin
we can also create a nft marketplace on
top of ethereum or a decentralized
exchange or a v5
farm or a blockchain based video game
now all that will have to be on top of
the ethereum network and that will make
it super busy
now this congested network makes
ethereum have crazy transaction fees
sometimes like for example right now as
of today if you wanted to send me
30 dollars in the ethereum network you
will have to pay
30 dollars of transaction fees that's
insane another problem that ethereum and
bitcoin have is the fact that they
cannot talk to each other actually they
can talk to
anybody there is no interoperability
between blockchains and blockchains
should be able to talk to each other
now maybe you're wondering why should
blockchains talk to each other well the
answer to this is because right now as
you can see we have
an immense amount of coins we have an
immense amount
of blockchain and it's very unrealistic
to expect one coin
to win everybody to be the only coin
that we will use
now some coins are good as a store of
value other coins are good for privacy
other coins are good for speed other
ones are stable coins now
as you can see this means that we are
going to end up with an immense amount
of coins
now this means that blockchains should
be able to talk to each other
imagine if somebody told you that if you
use gmail you cannot
send an email to hotmail for example
that doesn't happen the reason why all
these
email things can talk to each other
because they all implement
the same protocol and it has to be the
same with blockchain now the last
problem of ethereum to this course is
the programming language that it uses
if you want to make a smart contract
you're going to have to learn the
ethereum programming language and that
is solidity solidity isn't a hard
programming language to make it looks
like
typescript actually but it does have
some disadvantages
first of all it's a new language and it
will be better for adoption and for
developer
interest if we could write contracts
let's say in programming languages that
we like let's say go
rust haskell webassembly these languages
don't only have
bigger communities which will be good
for ethereum and the crypto ecosystem
but also
they have standards they have best
practices they also are
safer and more secure keep in mind that
the programming language that we choose
to
write a smart contract is very important
because a smart contract
should be really safe so if we really
want governments or stock
markets or very big official
institutions to consider
running on crypto or doing things with
the blockchain
we need to build these things in
programming languages that could be
formally verified
tested or have an industry behind them
not something super new as solidity for
example
mr vitalik buttering one of the
co-founders of ethereum
came up with something called the
excalibility trilemma which is like
a triangle like this on this trilemma
are three properties that
cryptocurrencies should have scalability
or speed
decentralization and security the
problem is that according to him a
cryptocurrency can only have two of
those
you can be decentralized and secure but
you will be slow let's say like for
example bitcoin
or you can be secure and scalable but
that means that you're not gonna be
decentralized so that would be like a
cryptocurrency controlled by a company
that they can just turn it off anytime
they want or you can be
scalable and decentralized but maybe
that means that you are not going to be
so secure but this was a long time ago
and there are some cryptocurrencies that
disagree
there are people that believe you can
have scalable fast
decentralized and secure
cryptocurrencies and those are called
third-generation blockchains now
ethereum is
transitioning to become a third
generation cryptocurrency
as well they're currently updating
ethereum to version number two
where ethereum is going to use 99.90
and percent less energy than before
and it will give them the ability to
process between 25 000 and 100
000 transactions per second so everybody
is really expected
on ethereum 2.0 so on the following
video we are going to explore
the world of the third generation
cryptocurrencies finally the stage has
been set and now
our players can come in now i've been
getting many comments asking me if i'm
going to launch an ecocoin or if i'm
going to make
an ethereum smart contract nft
course the answer to this is yes but
not on the way you think i'm not going
to make any ethereum
polka polkadot cosmos cardano course yet
and the reason why is because i
do not believe on any blockchain
platform
so far but i believe that this industry
is so far in like an
alpha state not even better yet in alpha
things are still breaking
things are changing and things are not
just good enough so this is why
i'm not making this kind of courses now
let's talk about
nico coin i'm also not going to launch
nico coin but instead what we're going
to do is i'm going to teach you
how you can launch your own
cryptocurrency today we're launching a
course where you are going to learn
how to create your own cryptocurrency by
implementing things like for example
peer-to-peer transactions
blockchain of course mining with
proof-of-work wallets
all that stuff in the go programming
language
so i'm not launching my own coin i'm
launching a course that teaches you
how to make a coin i think that to
understand something
you need to build it yourself so this is
what this course does
we don't talk about any platform we
don't use ethereum or whatever that is
we just do
our own coin to understand the basics
and to implement everything
using the beautiful awesome sexy go
programming language
this course is for educational purposes
only of course we're not going to
learn how to put our coin in an exchange
to make the next
dodge coin no it's only to understand
bitcoin and crypto and everything
from the inside so check out the link on
the description if that's something
you're interested on
and i will see you on the next video
thank you so much for watching
please be happy today don't forget to
eat kimchi ham sandida sarangayo see you
on the next one proof of steak coming up
bye